<post>
   <title>Staying healthy in times of lockdown</title>
   <date>2020-09-11</date>
   <body>
      <p>Here are some guidelines to living a sane life when the world seems to be falling to pieces. Most of these can be done in less than two minutes.</p>
	  <ul>
		<li>Keep your space clean. Whether you live in a small apartment or in a palace, it is much easier to feel happy in tidy surroundings than in a junkyard. Pick up a broom and sweep the floor. Put those empty glasses in the sink. Open a window and let some fresh air enter.</li>
		<li>Meditate. It is much easier than it sounds: simply focus on your breathing for a minute, or concentrate on the sounds you hear. When you do this regularly, you will notice it having a positive effect on your mood.</li>
		<li>Mental exercise. Try to read a book, or keep a diary. Don't spend entire days watching YouTube videos or reading Reddit posts. Keeping your mind busy is one of the best forms of therapy you can practice.</li>
		<li>Physical exercise. Lift some weights, or simply go for a walk. Practice yoga if you are into that. This is not about becoming fit, it's about getting your muscles warm and your blood flowing.</li>
		<li>Communicate with the people around you. Social distancing does not mean you have to be alone. It means you have to avoid getting close physically with too many people.  Give your parents a call. Go for a walk with somebody. Write an old-fashioned letter if you are into that.</li>
		<li>Sleep. I find this to be the hardest one, but try to go to sleep at a reasonable hour. Being rested is half the work to feeling well mentally.</li>
		<li>Be kind. Both to others and to yourself. Try not to judge. Focus on the good things.</li>
	  </ul>
	  <p>This is not always easy and will require minimal effort. But the good news is that you can do all of these things in very small steps. And even if you only manage to do a few of these, and you only do them once a week, don't be angry with yourself. I find that the greatest favor you can do yourself is to be acceptive. Even if you feel you are in a bad place, know that you did everything right. You are a star. Caress your soul. </p>
   </body>
</post>
