<post>
   <title>I miss going to work</title>
   <date>2020-11-21</date>
   <body>
      <p>Unlike many IT workers, it seems, I miss working from the office.</p>
      <p>Let's start with the commute. Yes, everybody hates commuting, and I can guarantee that I will curse the Belgian train system the very first day I'm going back to work, with its delays and overcrowded trains (well, I hope that last thing  will stay away for a while).
      But at the same time, I miss my 20 minute train ride that I spend with a book or a podcast, while I look out the window and mentally prepare for a new day. At my stopover, I would chat with colleagues who were waiting for the same train. I can't do that anymore.</p>
      <p>I miss sitting in a group of people while I work. I'm lucky to work in a well designed office with lots of space, where you don't have to fight for your . </p>
      <p>I miss having face to face interactions with people. I hate chatting and video meetings. They are so much more <a href="https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20200421-why-zoom-video-chats-are-so-exhausting">exhausting</a> than talks with people in the same room. </p>
      <p>It is difficult to find a good work-life balance. I start working when I get up. I try to end my work at a reasonable hour, but if I get an idea I might just turn my computer back on and continue working. The barrier is just not there anymore. It doesn't help that I live in a tiny apartment - my living room and my office are the same place, so it's hard to remember what I am doing at any given point. I might start browsing the internet during my work, or I might check my work email when the day is over. I will try to put my computer away at a predefined hour. Maybe it helps.</p>
      <p>In the end, I think socializing is a key part of any job where you work in a team. I'll isolate for as long as it's needed, but afterwards I will be glad to go back to work. I certainly don't envy the companies that have decided to go full remote, in fact I wonder how you can still have a connection to your organization or any sense of purpose when you're in that situation. In that case, work becomes a trade of time for money, and that is something I am not willing to accept at this point.</p>
   </body>
</post>
